[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 18]
[Five years later]
[2018]
Hello.
Please check out Qilewuqiong Bike-sharing.
Explore green,
low-carbon mode of transportation.
Just scan this code.
Hello.
Please check out Qilewuqiong Bike-sharing.
Explore green,
low-carbon mode of transportation.
-Check out Qilewuqiong Bike-sharing.
-Duan Qiyan has transformed
from Duan to Mr. Duan.
In college,
he kept sending us
the video clip of him
winning the championship
in the college venture competition with a huge lead.
In the video,
Duan Qiyan talks confidently
about the bike-sharing project
called Qilewuqiong,
describing the blueprint for solving
the city's last-mile travel problem.
Check out Qilewuqiong Bike-sharing.
You say this promoter
doesn't look like him?
Because that's not him.
He's the one next to him.
Mr. Duan, they won't take the flyers.
How many times have I told you?
I'm not Mr. Duan right now.
I'm Qiqi—
Qiqi from Qilewuqiong.
Hey, Handsome.
I can tell you're a sporty boy
at a glance.
Do you usually like riding bicycles?
Look at these bikes, aren't they cool?
If you think so,
hurry up and ask your parents
to scan the code for you.
I will give you a little gift.
Baby, what's going on?
Mom, scan the code.
You must still remember Tang Tingting.
Back then, she was almost scammed
while chasing her idol.
[Star Shine Media]
A few of us friends
helped her get back at them.
[Star Shine Media reading shelf]
Although Duan Qiyan always mocked her
for being bad at studying,
think about it—
how bad can the worst student
in the province's best high school's
experimental class
really be?
[Star Shine Media]
She was admitted to Zhendan University
to study media.
Upon graduation,
she decided to put into practice
what it would be like
to turn her hobby into a job.
Sure enough,
it's not great.
Mr. Wang,
I'll take up 5 more minutes of your time.
Our Su Mo is really good.
Whether it's singing, dancing, or sports—
he is proficient in all kinds of talents.
And he can endure a lot of hardship.
During his filming last time,
his leg was fractured from wire work.
He continued to film
the dialogue scenes with a cast on.
All our upcoming roles
require a more mature look.
Your Su...
That's no problem.
Aren't actors
supposed to shape their roles?
How can every role be custom-made?
I think as long as he understands
the character well,
and with the makeup and styling,
looking 5 to 6 years older
is definitely not a problem.
He is indeed not bad.
But for the upcoming roles,
Mr. Zheng has almost finalized them.
Let's work together
next time when there's a chance.
I...
Director Li?
You've reached the second basement level?
Okay, I'll come pick you up right away.
All right.
Mr. Wang...
Tang, please stay.
No need to see me off.
Our next step
is to optimize our system architecture.
We will use Java's
Spring Boot
framework to restructure the backend
to ensure an increase in operational
and maintenance efficiency.
We have also independently developed
an intelligent monitoring system
to better monitor
the status of our vehicles.
Mr. Liu, won't you take another look?
Mr. Liu!
Well...
That was an investor just now.
He
insisted on investing in our project.
But to be honest,
we don't usually consider
small fund firms like them.
What's up?
Agent Tang,
you're here talking business today too?
Yes.
Our Su Mo is very popular now.
Several big projects are fighting for him.
I'm here to reject Mr. Wang.
I can't even schedule all his projects.
I'm just afraid of offending people.
I'm going to be honest—
this Su Mo isn't even as handsome as me.
With so many big stars
in your company,
why insist on managing him?
What do you know?
Our Su Mo is a future top star.
Mind your own business.
I tried your shared bike last time,
it felt like riding a spin bike.
It was so exhausting.
Do something about it.
Okay, I got it.
Then...
Good... bye?
Bye-bye.
All right then.
Well,
bye-bye.
Bye.
[Lin Zhixia]
Shen Fuxuan went to study abroad alone.
Many mornings,
I would see Shen Fuxuan's Moments.
In the first few months,
there were many likes and comments.
Later, there were fewer and fewer.
Everyone is busy.
I was busy with my doctoral courses,
and he was busy with his internship.
The rainy nights
and moon of a foreign land
separated us from Shen Fuxuan.
Jin Baihui is still the same,
never slacking.
She gave up
the early admission to other schools
and entered Qingbei University's
Information Engineering Department
based on her college entrance exam result.
Then she continued to study every day
without fail.
She's in her second year
of grad school this year.
It's said she's already studying
for her PhD exams.
She really is the Jin Baihui
who can stir up a storm
wherever she goes.
Have you familiarized yourself
with the topic presentation
you're giving in a few days?
Yes.
I can present it anytime.
Electronic devices
are highly affordable nowadays.
If you like this kind of digital watch,
why not replace it with a smart band?
It can track your sleep
and heart rate too.
It's different.
You have no idea.
This watch
used to have stars on its display.
But it's been broken for 2 years.
Who would wear a watch
that can't tell time?
Me.
When Jiang Yubai gave me this watch,
he said
he had an identical one.
When the two watches
approach each other,
shining stars
appear on the watch face.
Although mine no longer tells time,
and the owner of the other watch
already vanished into the crowd,
I'm still wearing it,
as if wearing a silent universe
on my wrist.
But, Jiang Yubai,
we have been
out of contact for 5 years.
Where on earth are you?
[Star Shine Media]
Tingting.
I think if we have to
choose one out of four,
we can choose Director Zhang's.
It's a rare opportunity.
This one too.
The second male lead
has a lot of screen time.
What are you doing?
Just looking is useless.
Let's play cards.
This Ace represents Director Zhang's
fame and resources.
["Against the Wind"
Directed by Zhang Wendi]
This second male lead role
has good screen time and exposure—
["Retaliate"
Directed by Sun Yumeng]
let's give it a King.
This adaptation is good,
but the screen time is slightly less
than the second male lead role—
["One Light"
Directed by Lian Linhao]
I give it a Queen.
I know you don't like this drama,
so let's give it a 3.
["Train to Morning"
Directed by Li Cheng]
Suppose our current market
is a card table.
With your status and popularity,
which card do you think you are?
I'm developing steadily now...
let's say a Five.
I have a bit more experience than you,
so I'll choose a 6.
This rookie director,
let's give him a 7.
Now is the time to see our luck.
Shuffle the cards and draw one.
["Against the Wind"] ["Retaliate"]
I shall draw this card.
This Ace seems the biggest
and the most domineering.
["Against the Wind"] ["Retaliate"]
But when a 5 like you
is paired with the Ace,
the Ace is the one that stands out,
not you.
Same goes for these two scripts.
["One Light"] ["Train to Morning"]
As for this 3—
while it seems the smallest,
["One Light"] ["Train to Morning"]
it has a solid script
and an imaginative rookie director.
This is the card
you can really combine with.
It's like your own traits,
continuous effort,
and other opportunities
you might encounter in the future—
these often combine together
to create greater possibilities.
Its potential
is often greater than this single Ace.
So which one do you choose now?
I understand.
I don't want to play a single Ace.
I want to form a straight.
I choose this 3.
After joining the crew,
work harder.
It will be fine.
Don't worry.
When have I ever let you down?
Zhixia.
I have something to tell you.
What's wrong, Shuwen?
Zhixia, can I ask you a favor?
What is it?
You know I've deferred my graduation
for 2 years.
If I defer it again this year,
I won't be able to get my master's degree.
I heard
Tan Qianche's research group
will definitely pass.
I really need this project.
Can you vote for me later?
You're not the only candidate.
Xu Nuo has been following this—
I know.
But there's only one spot left
in the research group.
If I can't get into this group,
I'll definitely be doomed again this year.
Zhixia, please do me this favor.
Not being able to graduate
is a dead end.
In society,
it's basically murder.
I'm begging you.
Please.
In the upcoming review,
the key is not
who needs this position more,
but who can better represent our group's
future output and image.
Everyone needs to weigh this carefully.
We must differentiate the big picture
from personal feelings.
Especially Ms. Lin.
Your opinion always carries
a lot of weight,
and you see things clearly.
Your vote
determines the project's academic purity
and how far it can go.
I believe
you will certainly make
the most objective choice
that is most in line with the long-term
interests of the research group.
Right?
Zhixia.
I'll see to it.
Thank you.
Thanks.
I'll make it up to you.
Qianche's research group
is still short of one person.
[Tan Qianche Research Group Candidate
Voting Meeting]
As usual, we will
select one from the graduate students
in the department.
Zhixia,
Zheng, Qin,
Hou, and Xiong.
The five of you have
no conflict of interest with this project.
You will vote.
[Tan Qianche Research Group Candidate
Voting Meeting]
The candidates are Yang Shuwen and Xu Nuo.
You are all friends,
don't be constrained.
Vote for whoever you want.
Let's begin.
Then... Then I'll go first.
I vote
for Yang Shuwen.
I vote for Xu Nuo.
I vote for Yang Shuwen.
It's a two-to-two tie.
It seems everyone has thought it through.
This most crucial vote,
Zhixia,
is up to you.
I vote for Xu Nuo.
Let me introduce.
These two
are Jin Baihui's parents,
Jin Quan and Zhang Li.
We are old friends.
Yes.
This is Li Zhe's mother.
Her husband
is the president
of the Huacheng Chamber of Commerce.
She's here today to...
Let me say it.
My son, Li Zhe,
is a classmate
of your daughter, Jin Baihui.
Jin Baihui is studying
Information Engineering,
and Li Zhe is studying philosophy.
Philosophy.
Baihui is really excellent.
My son has seen her
at school several times.
He always tells me when he gets home
about how he has never
seen a girl
with such clear logical thinking,
such a clean temperament,
and so beautiful.
Young people,
they just want to make friends.
Our Baihui
just loves to read and study.
She's not as good as you say.
You really flatter her.
Yes.
It's because you two raised her well.
Mrs. Li,
the Jins are from a scholarly family.
They've been strict
with Baihui since she was little.
I've seen it all.
Yes.
Then Li Zhe must be very excellent too.
When we see Baihui,
we will definitely
have a good talk with her.
Yes.
Exactly.
I came today
just for this.
I've also spoken
to my husband about this.
He said
young people should learn from each other
and make progress together.
As parents,
we should try our best
to create some conditions for them.
Exactly.
As parents,
we have to think ahead about everything
and look at the big picture.
How about we see if Baihui
is busy right now
and make a video call to her?
We won't be disturbing her study, will we?
-No.
-It's okay.
We always call her anyway.
Girls need to be raised strictly.
Right, let's call her.
Show Baihui some concern.
Dad, what's wrong?
I'm busy running data.
It's nothing.
[Microphone] [Speaker] [Camera]
Have you eaten?
Look at you, you've lost weight recently.
I've told you,
to eat well and sleep well.
Don't stay up late, you know?
I forgot. I'll eat in a bit.
Baihui, listen to your dad.
[Microphone] [Speaker] [Camera]
Your dad is right.
Health is the capital of the revolution.
You must eat your meals.
Do you hear me?
[Microphone] [Speaker] [Camera]
Girls
shouldn't work too hard.
Okay.
By the way, look.
Look, who's this?
[Microphone] [Speaker] [Camera]
Ms. Chen. Do you remember her?
Baihui, I miss you.
This lady over here
is your classmate Li Zhe's mother.
Say hello.
Hello.
Hi, Ms. Li.
Sorry, I've been busy
with school recently,
and I haven't had time to visit you.
I apologize.
It's okay, it's okay.
Okay, I know you're busy.
I know you're busy.
I won't disturb your studies.
It's fine, just call us more often.
[Microphone] [Speaker] [Camera]
Make sure you eat your meals.
We're hanging up now.
Okay, bye-bye.
Zhixia.
Don't you think the vote just now
was too coincidental?
[Qingbei University]
[Quantum Bits and Computing]
Statistically,
low-probability events do happen.
No, they deliberately made it a tie
to force you to take a stand.
I know.
[Qingbei University]
[Quantum Bits and Computing]
The way they voted just now,
looked like they had rehearsed it.
It must have been
Tan Qianche's instruction.
Then why didn't you vote for Yang Shuwen?
I didn't vote for Xu Nuo
just to break the tie,
but because she is really suitable
for this project.
I've helped revise
everyone's master's thesis
in our department.
I know Shuwen
needs this project to graduate,
and I know Tan Qianche
is forcing me to take a stand.
No matter who I vote for,
they will hate me.
I just think
scientific research is not about politics
or favors.
Academics cannot lie.
Ms. Lin Zhixia,
I have something to say to you.
Do you know
that your vote was the deciding one?
Because of you,
I might really not graduate this year.
Lin Zhixia,
why are you doing this to me?
Shuwen, you should know very well
that your research direction
does not align with Tan Qianche's project.
Even if you do join,
this project won't give you any advantage.
You will just be a marginal figure.
I don't care.
As long as you vote for me,
I can graduate.
What about Xu Nuo?
She's also in her second year
of her master's program.
For the past 2 years,
she has spent all her time
on this research topic.
She worked uncredited for 2 years.
Shouldn't she be in this group?
Now you are reasoning with me.
Aren't there people
in the research group too?
People should consider feelings.
I help you, you help me.
What has Xu Nuo helped you with?
Last year, for your thesis,
I did my best to help you run the data.
Why can't you help me?
It's exactly because you helped me,
I couldn't vote for you.
The sub-project Tan Qianche gave you
is just scraps from his paper.
While Xu Nuo's model
is the real direction
that can aim for top journals.
If I voted for you,
it would be pushing you
into a pit of fire.
You can graduate,
but as long as you stay in this industry,
you'll find that
except for the empty title
of Tan Qianche's research group,
you have nothing.
Shuwen, I should help you,
but not by giving you a ticket
to a dead end.
Instead, while there's still time,
I should tell you
to take a different path.
A different path?
What path?
If I can't join this group,
I can't graduate.
Do I have any other path I can take?
I'll figure something out. I promise.
You... stop saying these useless things.
Meeting a heartless person like you
who bites the hand that feeds you,
I count myself unlucky.
Growing up is just so frustrating.
[Find what's new around you]
[Jiang Yubai]
[Jiang Yubai appears in the alumni directory
of Nanhai No. 1 High School]
"Lin Lin Lin Lin Lin Zhixia."
I announce that from now on,
you are my friend,
my best friend.
"Jiang Jiang Jiang Jiang Jiang Yubai"?
Actually, I've been wanting to ask you.
Why did you come back this time?
For you.
This beam of light took 8.6 years
to reach Earth.
That means before we even met,
it had already embarked
on the journey to meet us.
Duan Qiyan and the others
are my good friends,
but you're more like
my binary star partner.
We will advance along different orbits,
but our center will always be the same.
[Jiang Yubai, are you there?]
Jiang Yubai.
Where exactly are you?
Hurry, the defibrillator!
Hurry!
Mom!
[Repayment plan for the next 7 months:
437,000]
[Qingbei University]
Have you heard?
Dr. Lin from our university
will give us a sharing today.
Really?
I heard she entered our university
through early admission.
Here she comes.
[Qingbei University]
Ms. Lin is so pretty.
She really is.
She's not only an overachieving scholar,
but also a gorgeous lady.
[Qingbei University]
[Quantum Bits and Computers]
Today I'll be talking about
quantum bits and computers.
A classical computer bit is like a switch—
it's either 0 or 1.
But a quantum bit,
is more like
a spinning top rotating
in two opposite directions simultaneously.
[The superposition state of a quantum bit]
Mathematics proved
that using vectors in a Hilbert space
[The "perfect description" in math]
can perfectly represent
this state of simultaneous rotation.
[Quantum Bits and Computers]
On this ordinary afternoon,
the stars surprisingly showed up again.
The slight heat from the dial plate
is the temperature deep in my memory
that never cooled down.
You told me that you wouldn't be far away
as long as the stars were sparkling.
Jiang Yubai,
have you always been around?
Did you never leave me?
Master Jiang.
The telescope you left on the mountain,
can it really capture stars?
You're amazing.
You can fix appliances
and do crafts.
You can even capture stars.
You really are a master.
Go back once you get the stuff.
I have something to do.
Master Jiang, then...
I'll be leaving.
Top student,
it's time to pay the money back.
Wow, you can even do this.
Amazing.
Six.
Okay, just right.
I'm leaving.
[Repayment plan for the next 7 months:
437,000]
[Meet Lin Zhixia]
♪ With every breath, the shadows creep ♪
♪ A demon in disguise ♪
♪ Talking the sweetest lies ♪
♪ It tries to drown me in my sleep ♪
"Jiang Jiang Jiang Jiang Jiang Yubai."
♪ Pain comes like a tide ♪
♪ It hurts,
but I'm way too tired to hide ♪
♪ Will you please hold me, help me
walk out of this endless night ♪
♪ I've lost my light and power ♪
♪ Lost my will to fight ♪
♪ Will you stay by my side ♪
Miss.
It's not that I don't want to help you.
The chip in this watch of yours
is different from standard ones.
Its code is encrypted.
Even if it's broken,
it's not something
that can be easily fixed.
This firmware
has been overwritten so many times
that it has basically reached its limit.
Unless you can find
the person who flashed this firmware,
otherwise, if you force it,
it's very likely that this watch
will be completely ruined.
That would be a problem.
Please see if there are any other ways.
This watch is very important to me.
I can pay extra.
As much as you want.
It's not about the money.
Let me put it this way—
this code encryption
is like the person who made this watch
put a combination lock on it.
The rest of us
can try to crack the code.
If we're lucky,
we might open it on the first try.
But if we try a few times
and get it wrong,
the lock will protect itself
and lock itself down.
Then no one will be able to open it.
So this is very risky.
I really don't dare to take this job.
I'm sorry.
Sorry to bother you then.
It's okay.
Hey, Miss.
Miss.
My name's Cheng.
Can I help you?
I might have a way to fix that watch.
I know a master.
His skills are very advanced.
He specializes in fixing weird things.
Things that can't be fixed
in these places can't stump him.
How about this?
If it's okay,
let's add each other on WeChat.
I'll take the watch
and show it to our master.
If he can't fix it,
I promise to return it exactly as it is.
You have nothing to lose.
But I've asked many places.
This kind of self-encrypted code,
if it can't be decrypted,
it's very likely to be damaged.
I know.
Our master also does computer decryption.
He's really amazing.
Your watch isn't that complicated.
Last time he even fixed
a brainwave controller
modified from a handheld game console.
I'll take it back for him to see.
If he can't fix it,
it's free.
-But if it's fixed...
-I'll pay whatever it takes.
All right, come on,
let's add each other on WeChat.
Brother Jiang, this is a big job.
A programmed electronic watch is broken.
I took a quick look.
The encryption algorithm
inside is very complicated.
I can't figure it out.
Can you take a look?
I need to speed up paying off my debts.
I'm not available this month.
The client said
as long as it can be fixed,
they'll pay any price.
This watch seemed
very important to that lady.
If you can fix it,
we'll make a fortune.
Just take a look.
It's easy money.
Where did this come from?
What do you mean?
Where did this watch come from?
F-From the watch shop.
When I was looking for work,
a lady was asking around
if this watch could be fixed.
What's wrong?
Master Jiang, what's wrong?
I can't fix it.
Hey...
You...
You haven't even taken a closer look.
Jiang?
Master Jiang?
All right.
I'll reply to her then.
Miss Lin, I'm sorry.
I showed it to my master.
He said it can't be fixed.
How about I send it back to you tomorrow?
Thank you anyway.
I'll ask someone else.
Jiang, I'm leaving.
Wait a minute.
The watch...
leave it here.
Didn't you just say you couldn't fix it?
Just leave it here.
I'll take another look.
I might not be able to fix it.
Don't tell her yet.
Okay.
Then I'll get going.
[Cheng]
You're still here,
right?
But where are you now?
I kind of...
miss you.
It's really fixed.
I told you our Master Jiang is amazing.
He can fix anything.
He's just been too busy lately,
so he didn't agree at first.
What did you call him?
M-Master Jiang.
My master's surname is Jiang.
They say he used to be a top student.
By the way, I sent the bill to your phone.
Miss, please pay the bill.
We're here.
This used to be my family's garage.
We rented it to him later.
Jiang!
Jiang?
The client who had her watch fixed
last time
insists on thanking you in person.
Brother Jiang.
[Watch out for the train]
That's weird. He was just here.
How strange.
Where did he run off to?
Where could he be?
[Watch out for the train]
[Bai]
Find a way to send her away.
Just say I'm not here.
Damn.
What?
[Watch out for the train]
Nothing. It's not him.
I just remembered.
We have an external job today.
He might have gone out.
But I just heard a noise inside.
You must have misheard.
This crappy warehouse
makes noise whenever the wind blows.
Master Jiang
probably went out.
He won't be back for a while.
Miss Lin, why don't you go back first?
No need.
He'll come back, right?
I'll wait for him right here.
I have nothing going on today anyway.
Well...
With his temper,
you'll be waiting for nothing.
It's fine.
I'll wait until he comes back.
You...
[Bai]
Just leave it.
Miss Lin,
he won't be back for a while.
Why don't you wait,
and I'll leave first?
Thank you.
As I stood in front of this door,
I didn't know
if it was Jiang Yubai behind it.
Nor did I know
if Jiang Yubai wanted to see me.
Perhaps,
what separates us is not just time,
but completely different paths,
and unspeakable realities.
I realized
♪ Only for this lingering warmth
of the moment ♪
♪ Trading souls with the night ♪
♪ Every dusk I have stolen ♪
♪ Foretells a parting ♪
♪ Where did the storm start brewing ♪
♪ Drenching you before we knew it? ♪
♪ Let me draw near to you ♪
♪ Let me imagine you ♪
♪ Let me sink into your ♪
♪ Scattered golden glow ♪
♪ Let the night blur your figure ♪
♪ Yet tear myself away from you ♪
♪ I can't fathom why ♪
♪ I've never truly possessed you ♪
♪ That blazing, radiant feeling ♪
♪ Once the rain stops, clouds disperse ♪
♪ Hence I lose you, time and again ♪
♪ Let me draw near to you ♪
♪ Let me imagine you ♪
♪ Let me sink into your ♪
♪ Scattered golden glow ♪
♪ Let the night blur your figure ♪
♪ Yet tear myself away from you ♪
♪ I can't fathom why ♪
♪ I've never truly possessed you ♪
♪ That blazing, radiant feeling ♪
♪ Once the rain stops, clouds disperse ♪
♪ Hence, time and again, I lose ♪
I want to be with you forever.
♪ Myself ♪
You will always be my one and only...
best friend.
♪ Let the wind pass you ♪
♪ I'll never respond again ♪
♪ I thought I could ♪
♪ Forget ♪
"Lin Lin Lin Lin Lin Zhixia."
♪ With every breath, the shadows creep ♪
♪ A demon in disguise ♪
♪ Talking the sweetest lies ♪
♪ It tries to drown me in my sleep ♪
♪ Pain comes like a tide ♪
♪ It hurts,
but I'm way too tired to hide ♪
♪ Will you please hold me, help me
walk out of this endless night ♪
♪ I've lost my light and power ♪
♪ Lost my will to fight ♪
♪ Will you stay by my side ♪
♪ Be my light tonight ♪
♪ Let's run away ♪
♪ Embrace the light ♪
♪ With you, I'll win this fight ♪
♪ Let's run away ♪
♪ No time to cry ♪
♪ Your love will guide us
through the night ♪
♪ It tries to drown me in my sleep ♪
♪ Pain comes like a tide ♪
♪ It hurts,
but I'm way too tired to hide ♪
♪ Will you please hold me, help me
walk out of this endless night ♪